Rithesh Kumar

Research Scientist at Adobe Research

+1 438-921-8291 | ritheshkumar.95@gmail.com | https://github.com/ritheshkumar95 | LinkedIn

Summary

I am an AI researcher with expertise in deep learning and generative modelling. Prior to Adobe, I was the Technical Lead for the Overdub Research team at Descript Inc. where I led the development of the flagship <u>Overdub</u> and <u>Regenerate</u> features. I completed my MSc in Computer Science (specializing in Artificial Intelligence) at Mila lab in Université de Montréal supervised by Prof. Yoshua Bengio.

Experience

Research Scientist, Adobe Research, Toronto, Ontario	Aug 2023—Current
Al Researcher, Descript, Montréal, Québec	Nov 2018-Aug 2023
Research Intern, Microsoft Research - Montréal, Québec	Feb 2018—Sep 2018
Research Intern, Lyrebird.ai, Montréal, Québec	May 2017—Feb 2018
Research Collaborator (remote), Mila - Université de Montréal	Apr 2016—May 2017
Research Intern, Serre Lab, Brown University	Jun 2016-Aug 2016

Sep 2017-Aug 2019

Aug 2013-Apr 2017

Education

M.Sc. Computer Science (Artificial Intelligence)	
--	--

Université de Montréal (Mila), Montréal, Québec

Research Supervisor: Prof. Yoshua Bengio

CGPA: 4.15 / 4.3

B.E, Computer Science and Engineering

Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

CGPA: 8.63 / 10.0 (Rank 46 among 16,449 candidates)

Publications

High-Fidelity Audio Compression using Improved RVQGAN [paper]

Rithesh Kumar*, Prem Seetharaman*, Alejandro Luebs, Ishaan Kumar, Kundan Kumar (Submitted) Poster Presentation - NeurIPS 2023

VampNet: Music Generation via Masked Acoustic Token Modeling [paper]

Hugo Flores Garcia, Prem Seetharaman, **Rithesh Kumar**, Bryan Pardo Poster Presentation - ISMIR 2023

Chunked Autoregressive GAN for Conditional Waveform Synthesis [paper]

Max Morrison, **Rithesh Kumar**, Kundan Kumar, Prem Seetharaman, Aaron Courville, Yoshua Bengio Poster Presentation - ICLR 2022

NU-GAN: High resolution neural upsampling with GAN [paper]

Rithesh Kumar, Kundan Kumar, Vicki Anand, Yoshua Bengio, Aaron Courville Hosted at Arxiv

MelGAN: Generative Adversarial Networks for Conditional Waveform Synthesis [paper] [blog]

Kundan Kumar*, **Rithesh Kumar***, Thiubault de Boissiere, Lucas Gestin, Wei Zhen Teoh, Jose Sotelo, Alexandre de Brebisson, Yoshua Bengio, Aaron Courville

Poster Presentation - NeurIPS 2019

Maximum Entropy Generators for Energy-Based Models [paper]

Rithesh Kumar, Sherjil Ozair, Anirudh Goyal, Aaron Courville, Yoshua Bengio Masters Thesis

ObamaNet: Photo-realistic lip-sync from text [paper] [website]

Rithesh Kumar, Jose Sotelo, Kundan Kumar, Alexandre de Brébisson, Yoshua Bengio Oral Presentation - NIPS 2017 ML for Creativity and Design Workshop

SampleRNN: An Unconditional End-to-End Neural Audio Generation Model [paper]

Soroush Mehri, Kundan Kumar, Ishaan Gulrajani, **Rithesh Kumar**, Shubham Jain, Jose Sotelo, Aaron Courville, Yoshua Bengio

Poster Presentation - ICLR 2017 Conference Track

Selected Projects

Reproducing Neural Discrete Representation Learning [github] [report]

Jan 2018-Apr 2018

Rithesh Kumar, Tristan Deleu, Evan Racah - Mila

Peproduced and analyzed Vector Quantized Variati

Reproduced and analyzed Vector-Quantized Variational Autoencoders (VQ-VAEs)(IFT 6135 - Representation Learning course final project)

Dec 2016-Jan 2017

Reproducing WYSIWYG: Visual Markup Decompiler [github]

Rithesh Kumar, Rithesh Rohan, U. Sivashanmugam - SSNCE
Developed a software tool to deconstruct image of math equations to its corresponding LaTeX markup (Undergraduate final project)

Relevant Courses and Skills

Graduate

IFT 6135 - Representation Learning - Prof. Aaron Courville

COMP 767 - Reinforcement Learning - Prof. Doina Precup

IFT 6269 - Probabilistic Graphical Models - Prof. Simon Lacoste-Julien

IFT 6080 - Duckietown (Autonomous Vehicles) - Prof. Liam Paull

MOOCs

<u>Data Science Specialization</u> - Johns Hopkins University (Coursera)